Hello
Здравствуйте
You are from Ukraine As I understand it Yes you are from
Вы из Украины Я так понимаю Да вы из
Russia
России
Yes there is St. Petersburg there is the city of Khmelnytsky
Да есть Питера есть города Хмельницкий
war talk
войне разговаривать
you are not tired of talking already
вы не задолбала уже говорить
Well let's talk about something
Ну давайте о чем-нибудь поговорим
Well no I don't play But I
Ну нет не играю Но
played of course but I know how to play and you are
играл конечно но я знаю как играть а вы
here about the war Come talk
сюда о войне Приходите говорить
No, I really miss it here, I’m on
Нет я на самом деле скучаю тут у меня
vacation now at the dacha from St. Petersburg,
отпуск сейчас на даче от Питера
far away on Ladoga, you know
далеко на Ладоге знаете
Well, I’m going to chat, but there are a lot of
Ну вот захожу пообщаться но очень много
negative people.
негативщиков
I don’t understand either. Why do many
Я тоже не понимаю будет Почему многие
Ukrainians immediately
украинцы они сразу негативно россиян
throw
кидают Блин мне вот много русских
Russians negatively?  and your
русских уже жалуются я захожу а ваши
Ukrainians throw negative I don’t understand either,
украинцы негатив кидать Я тоже не
so I don’t understand these people if
понимаю вот я не понимаю этих людей если
you feel bad about some negative ones
Вам плохо какие-то негативные сидите
Choose Ukraine there, why do you
Выбирайте себе там Украины зачем вы
choose Russia, really, if I chose
выбираете Россию правда если я выбрал
Russia because I want nature about something
Россию потому что я хочу про что-то
detached from politics,
отстраненное политики
for example,
природу например
I don’t  I understand these people
Я не понимаю этих людей
, they are ready to talk about nature
вот о природе готовы говорить
without stopping, and now at the dacha And
не останавливаясь и вот сейчас на даче И
in fact, here, well, Ladoga fishing
на самом деле здесь ну Ладога рыбалка
for perch is  we drill straight run after
за окунем бегаем сверлим прям бегайте за
perch out of the blue no fish
окунем измолку нет рыба
Well
Ну
[music]
[музыка]
winter fishing for perch looks
зимняя рыбалка на окуня выглядит таким
like that you don’t sit on one hole
образом что ты на одной лунке не сидишь
you look for it you drill in different places
ты ищешь его сверлишь разных местах
Well this is such a very long topic new
Ну это такая очень долгая тема новая
specifics and I enjoy not
специфика и Я получаю удовольствие не
sitting in a tent with a roach  to catch
сидя в палатке плотвичку ловить там да
some kind of fish there But it’s precisely
какую-то рыбку А вот именно окуня
to catch a perch predator And for this you need to
хищника ловить И для этого надо
drill sometimes many dozens of holes,
просверлить иногда много десятков лунок
it happens of course you’re lucky you can catch the first one
бывает конечно повезет можно на первую
right away Well, this is
сразу наловить Ну это
a separate topic.
отдельная такая тема Вот отдыхаю рыбачу
I still have
помещении у меня тут еще
electric heaters in the room, so
электрообогреватели стоят так что
I liked everything so much the fairy tale
все мне так понравилась сказка Повторите
Repeat again and please I listened fell
еще раз и пожалуйста Я прослушал заснул
asleep Where is the
На каком месте
fishing Ok we run after the perch
рыбалка Ок бегаем за окунем я
I imagined how it is to run by the hand
я вообразил как это бежать за руку
Let's once again
Давайте еще раз
what are you laughing at me but Well,
чего вы смеетесь мне но Ну
not that  so that you run right after the perch,
не то чтобы прямо за окунем бежишь его
but where are you trying to find a flock,
да где вот стайку на пытаешься найти
because the perch Well, in one place
потому что окунь Ну вот в одном месте
it’s unlikely to shoot directly
вряд ли прямо прострелился и там прям
you’ll probably need to
что-то наловишь скорее всего надо много
drill a lot of holes
лунок просверлить
to pick up a bait
подобрать приманку
there are metal spinners there are
есть металлические блесны есть
balancers it’s very interesting to catch a mormyshka,
балансиры можно на мормышку ловить очень
but if you do this I’m not
интересно но если этим занимаешься Я не
sure if you are interested in listening to it
уверен что вам это интересно слушать
[laughter]
[смех]
and it’s a mormyshka perch in the sun I
и она на солнце
wonder what  Damn,
мормышка окунь интересно что-то Блин
let's talk about something more
давайте поговорим о чем-нибудь более
interesting for you more interesting
интересным для вас более интересно
all the same in the war I when
все таки в войне Я когда вот кто-то
someone says war I'm already starting to
слова война Я уже начинаю эти
wake up war war NATO 9 years 8
просыпаться война война НАТО 9 лет 8
you will support a special operation
вы поддержите специальную операцию
Yes, I had no doubt
Да я не сомневался
because the person who  chooses
потому что человек который выбирает
Ukraine to talk about
Украину для того чтобы поговорить о
some crucian perches and is surprised
каких-то карасях окунях и удивляется А с
Why the hell is this person aggressing me here
какого фига на меня тут агрессирует это
or intellectually
человек или интеллектуально ограниченный
limited who you don’t look like so you can still
на которого вы не похожи так вы все-таки
see yes What
видно да Что
does this person mean cynical backdrop
значит этот человек циничный задник
Why uncovered why do you think so  Well,
Почему расчехлил почему так считаешь Ну
I've said my opinion, she's good. Well,
я вот сказал свое мнение она хорошо Ну
let's
ладно
continue, yes.
продолжим да
So what about the war
Так что там про войну
? Where did you bring up the city of Khmelnitsky  at the dacha there are pets
воспитана даче домашние животные есть
No, this is not a dacha
Нет это не дача
no dacha This is where Well, I go here four times a year
нет дача Это куда Ну я четыре раза в год
to spend the
сюда выезжаю провести
weekend now I have a vacation all my
выходные вот сейчас отпуск у меня весь
vacation
отпуск
and Khmelnitsky is here Do you think
а Хмельницкий это вот Как вы считаете
this
это
is a Russian city
это русский город
or Polish
или польский
let's start with fishing crucian carp is
давайте начнем с рыбалки карась это
Russian  fish No, seriously, crucian is a
русская рыба Не ну серьезно карась это
Russian fish,
русская рыба
for some reason, that is, you catch fish that are not Russian
почему то есть вы ловите рыбы не русская
Name some kind of Russian here Clear pike is
Назовите какой-то русская вот Ясная щука
better to eat a fairy tale by
лучше есть сказка
Emelya there At the pike's command And about
Емеля там По щучьему велению А про
crucian carp At least one fairy tale is there a
карася Хоть одна сказка есть ли про
specialist in Russian fairy tales about a perch with concepts There is a pike
специалист в русских сказках Есть щука
Yes,
да
Emelya was there, a fool on the stove, lay what
Емеля был там дурачок на печи лежала что
he was thinking there at the behest of a pike, And there are
там загадывал по щучьему велению А
others. There are also Goldfish, these are
другие еще Золотая рыбка есть вот это
Russian fish, and the perch is some kind of
русские рыбы а окунь это какая-то
NATO fish.
натовская рыба получается
I’m trying to find a topic, and
Ну я пытаюсь найти тему и вот про
you’re not interested in fishing, but you’re not interested in
рыбалку вам не интересно да про
Khmelnitsky, a Russian city or a Polish
Хмельницкий русский город или польский
one, but what’s interesting is
тоже не интересно а вот а что интересно
interesting  about st. petersburg is it a
интересно про санкт-петербург это
swedish or russian city
шведский или русский город
it is a russian city
это российский город
settled it became russian like a
оседали он стал российским как
Russian federation when it was founded
российских Федерации когда его основали
well in general
Ну вообще
1700 well everything before 1700 what was there
1700 Ну все до 1700 что там было
well there may have been some kind of city
Ну там возможно был какой-то город
impossible and a swedish fortress there
невозможно а шведская крепость там была
was this swedish land  primordially Swedish
вот эта шведская Земля исконно шведские
lands Yes,
земли Да
well, or not And where now
ну так или нет И где сейчас
where now so you ask
где сейчас так вы спрашиваете
Khmelnitsky is it a Russian city or
Хмельницкий это русский город или
Polish And where is Russia now
польский А где сейчас Россия
You look how far to Sweden And
Вы посмотрите сколько до Швеции А
how much from Khmelnitsky to Poland or to
сколько от Хмельницкого до Польши или до
Russia
России
That is, you have a
То есть у вас возникает у вас возникает
question Russian  or Polish is a city And
вопрос русский или польский это город А
about Peter
про Питер
Not well, about Khmelnitsky I can say quite
Не ну про Хмельницкий могу совершенно
clearly Here Well, if Ternopil is
четко сказать Вот Ну если Тернополь это
still closer to Poland, then
еще все-таки ближе к Польше то
Khmelnitsky It is already far from Poland,
Хмельницкий Это уже далеко от Польши
how much further than Ternopil is the
насколько дальше чем Тернополь
same from Lviv to Ternopil, this is
одинаково от Львова до Тернополя это
Ternopil to Khmelnitsky about the
Тернополя до Хмельницкого примерно
same distance  as far as plus or
одинаковое расстояние насколько плюс
minus, in general, we
минус в общем мы поняли что
realized that st.
санкт-петербург это исконно шведская
which in the 18th century was illegally taken away by
которая в 18 веке незаконно отобрано
some Germans Peter the first is
каким-то этом немцам Петром первым
absolutely legally
абсолютно законно
needed we must restore historical
нужны мы должны вернуть историческую
justice Moscow must return to the
справедливость Москва должна вернуться к
borders of one thousand three hundred of some year
границам тысячу триста какого-то года
Moscow is Moscow the city is
Москва есть Москва город есть
You must this is what
Вы должны это что такое
Sweden is I will take you away, that is, make a
Швеции Вас заберу то есть сделать
filtration measure  let's see who is
фильтрационные мероприятие посмотрим кто
normal who is a quilted jacket somewhere Siberia
нормальный кто [__] куда-то Сибирь
Why
Зачем в Москву поддерживаешь
do you support Moscow and everything you want to do there yes oh at least
а там все что хочешь делать да ох хоть
they fry each other perch
как окуня жарят друг друга
[laughter]
[смех]
funny guys Well the last question What
веселые дядька Ну последний вопрос Как
do you think After the defeat of Russia in
вы считаете После поражения России в
this war, it will fall apart into several
этой войне она распадется на несколько
states or  she’ll just have a
государств или у нее просто будет
coup and throw off one ruler
переворот и скинут одного правителя
to put another
поставить другого
well,
ну
about the defeat, it’s also a controversial moment
насчет поражения тоже спорный момент
in general,
вообще прям
it’s very unlikely,
маловероятно
let’s say it happened like that, they didn’t lose, no
допустим случилось так не проиграли нет
, the defeat happened,
случилось поражение
what it will look like This means that
каким оно будет выглядеть Это значит что
Ukrainian troops will enter the territory of
украинские войска зайдут на территорию
Russia,
России
take the main cities So the
берут основные города Так
Ukrainian troops can already watch
может смотреть войска украинский уже на
in Ross  and
территории России
they have already entered the territory of Russia, the
Они уже зашли на территорию России
question is that if Russia is
вопрос в том что если Россия терпит
defeated, this is how it should look. This
поражение это как должно выглядеть Это
means that your army is defeated. Ukraine is
значит что ваша армия разбита Украина
returning and the territory of 91 is imposing huge sanctions on you.
возвращается и территории 91 года на вас
Yes, and Ukrainian troops are taking Moscow.
Да и украинские войска берут Москву
Why?
Зачем
Well, I have a question, the
Ну у меня вопрос
Kadyrovites will take Moscow  Why the hell do we
кадыровцы возьмут Москву Нахрена нам
take Moscow there, we need this abscess. Why
брать Москву там нам этот гнойник Зачем
do we need a section there, the Kadyrovites will be
нужен там разделе банят кадыровцы татары
banished to Moscow, the Tatars will tear apart Damn everyone who
в Москву раздерут Блин всех кто хочет
wants to really tell them the world community, in
вот реально им мировое сообщество
short, Moscow robbed you,
сказать короче вот Вас Москва грабила
now you can plunder Moscow to take
теперь можете разграбить Москву забирать
away your regions, whatever you want, that
тащите свои регионы все что хотите да то
is, look at the mouse Why  us to attack
есть смотрите мышь Зачем нам нападать на
Moscow Russia because of the defeat in Ukraine
Москву Россия из-за поражения в Украине
and the withdrawal of troops Yes, it is already
и отвода войск Да она уже и так у вас
starting to ferment in you you already have no laws
начинает брожение у вас уже нет законов
there, it is recruiting convicts Yes, to the war Where will they
там зеков набирает Да на войну Куда эти
all throw themselves, they will return to the cities
все закинутся они вернутся в города А
Kadyrov's own personal army in the regions,
Кадырова свои личной армия в регионах
their governor's armies Yes, in fact,
свои армии губернатора Да есть по сути у
you already have feudalization in general  It
вас уже феодализация общества произошла
turns out that as a result of Russia,
получается что в результате Россия
all international, inter-social,
все междунациональные меж социальные
inter-religious contradictions not
межрелигиозные все противоречия не
only aggravate, but you, for example,
только обостряться да у вас например
how many last year, last year alone
Сколько за прошлый год только за прошлый
, 160 thousand Tajiks received
год 160 тысяч таджиков получили
Russian citizenship, you already have Russians, in
гражданство России у вас уже русских по
fact, no longer remain in your cities Well,
сути не остается в ваших городах Ну вы
you  you see it, you see it, plus you,
же это видите так видите плюс У Вас
for example, How many children, how many children do you have,
например Сколько детей сколько у вас
several, and the Chechens have four each,
детей несколько вот а у чеченцев у них
for example, in a generation
по четверо так например через поколение
you will be an ethnic minority, yes, the
вы будете этническим меньшинством да вас
world community will protect you as ethnic
мировое сообщество будет как этнические
minorities, because the politics of the
меньшины защищать потому что политика
world community Yes, it is necessary
мирового сообщество Да что надо
to develop the languages ​​of the fading  peoples will be,
развивать языки угасающих народов будут
for example, the Russian language twice a week.
например русский язык два раза в неделю
They will definitely be taught so that
Обязательно будут учить для того чтобы
this is an indigenous people
вот это коренной народ
and will study their language, and so it
и будет изучать его язык а так
will fall apart. And the meaning is the meaning Tell the
распадется А смысл смысл Вот скажите
Chechens the Yakuts And you live in one
чеченцам якутом И вам жить в одном
state
государстве
what is the meaning of
какой смысл
answer yes I allow Yes,
можно отвечать да разрешаю Да вот
look here  Well, this is the molasses in
смотрите вот Ну вот эта патока который в
which you believe  read it and savor it, this
которую вы верите и смакуете ее вот это
pseudo-
псевдо
future
псевдобудущие
drew it so interesting, but okay, I
нарисовали так интересно но ладно я вам
explained the situation to you like this, I sell
объяснила ситуацию такую я продаю
real estate my apartment that I
недвижимость свою квартиру который я
live in St. Petersburg and around March by
живу в Питере и примерно к Марту к
April I will already live in Crimea, I buy
апрелю я уже буду жить в Крыму я покупаю
a house there and start a business there Yes
себе там жилье и начинаю там бизнес Да
they really go there to live.
вот реально едут туда жить
I’m answering you everything is
Это я вам отвечаю на все
cool, I’m being honest. I’m addressing
круто я вот честно Я обращаюсь сейчас ко
all citizens of the Russian Federation now,
всем гражданам Российской Федерации
please, try to
пожалуйста чем побыстрее постарайтесь по
invest in Crimea before the summer with something, the
инвестировать в Крым до лета чем-то чем
more investments you build and
больше инвестиций построить и там что-то
buy something there,
купите там
it’s possible to develop this  the territory is
возможно развивать эту территорию это
very correct, seriously, why do we need to take this
очень правильно серьезно зачем нам это
murdered Crimea if we take it
убитый Крым забирать если мы заберем его
with your hut to
с вашей хатой
brow with all this And you
бровироваться вот этим всем А вы же
understand what really is such that Well,
понимаете что реально такова что Ну вот
well, the entire state of Ukraine ceases to
Ну вот всё государство Украины перестает
exist Well, in any case, Well,
существовать Ну во всяком случае Ну
maybe not completely, but for sure  not in
может быть не полностью но точно не в
the form in which it has always been
том виде в котором она всегда была
in Kherson on the cheap bought a hut type with
в Херсоне по дешёвке купил хата тип с
Russia Kherson
Россией Херсоне
but
но
childhood I go to the Crimea  I really love
детства езжу в Крым очень люблю
those places and they go there to live, we had
те места и едут туда жить у нас был
such a very activist Kirill’s
такой вот очень активист Кирилла стримы
mustache streamer mushroom picker loved Rybak he collected mushroom picker
усов грибник любил Рыбак он грибником
here and he also says to a peasant
собирал вот и он тоже мужику говорит
Crimea will also be very good now,
Крыму тоже будет очень хорошая сейчас
just on the cheap, people can now
как раз по дешевке можно сейчас люди
run away from Crimea Yes, therefore, you can buy
убегают из Крыма Да поэтому можно купить
cheaper there, it’s super Yes, nothing is
там подешевле это супер Да ничего там не
cheaper there, nothing is cheaper there, the
подешевле ничего там не подешевле
price of normal there is more expensive than in
подорожала нормальную там дороже чем в
St.
Питере чтобы
there it will not be destroyed, which
жилье если там она не будет разрушена
means the right investment,
значит правильное вложение
and in bakhmut and solidarity it is now profitable
а в бахмуте и солидаре сейчас выгодно
to buy real estate Do you think there is
покупать недвижимость Как вы думаете там
already little left alive there, but
уже вообще мало чего живого осталось но
in any case everything will be fine there it will be
по-любому там все хорошо будет там
profitable to buy there you would buy a hut there
выгодно покупать вы бы купили там хату
Well, maybe I won’t, this one, they
Ну вот можно я не буду вот этот вот не
don’t want to go there Yalta Simferopol Sevastopol
хотят там Ялта Симферополь Севастополь
Well, closer to Alushta  you
Ну ближе к Алуште Так а ну да Пока туда
can’t get haimar here yet you can still
не достают хаймар сюда пока еще можно
buy
покупать
carbon monoxide really
угарный дядька реально
Melitopol huts shorter now you can buy
Мелитополе хаты короче сейчас
Melitopol cherries there for
мелитопольскую черешню можно там
yourself you can buy a plantation there
плантацию себе купить можно
Kherson was Here Kherson in general Here is a super
Херсоне было Вот Херсон вообще Вот супер
investment of this summer it was Kherson all of
инвестиции этого лета это был Херсон вся
Russia came running shorter in Kherson
Россия прибежала короче в Херсоне хаты
to buy huts shorter for the first time I hear about
купить короче первый раз слышу про это и
I’m not interested in Melitopol,
вообще мне не интересует не Мелитополь
you hear,
слышишь
no, I want carbon monoxide My friend
нет так хочу угарного У меня друг там
has been working there for a long time Yes, if I bought it a long time ago
уже давно работает давно Да если давно
, I would believe But what he
еще купил я бы поверил А вот то что
wants
сейчас хочет
now No, now I’m not just going somewhere, I know where I’m
Нет сейчас еду не просто куда-то я знаю
going, here you are the main thing  you know that in
куда еду вот вы главное знаете что в
your molasses dreams there And some
своих паточных мечтах там И каких-то
illusions you imagine otherwise, well,
иллюзиях представляете себе иначе ну ну
okay, I won’t convince you Time
ладно я не буду переубеждать Время
will tell The main thing is you before you buy
покажет Главное вы перед тем как купить
There, first Sell in St. Petersburg and then
Там сначала Продайте в Питере и потом
buy
покупаете сразу же вылупите хорошо я так
immediately  there is something else not
и сразу постройте там еще что-то не
just bought that something else to finish building a
просто купили что что-то еще достроить
useful one was to drive a car there
полезненькое было машину пригоните туда
so that it was sure to be in the Crimea  Your
чтобы обязательно в Крыму была Ваша
car will be exactly like this and the TV will
машина именно так и будет телевизор
immediately take the toilet with you, this
унитаз сразу берите с собой то вот это
is important, everything is important, you will have to go
важно все важно придется придется идти
to the territory of Ukraine for the toilet, and there
на территорию Украины за унитазом а там
we don’t have Crimea for our toilets.
за своих унитазов у нас нет
at least one
воровали Вот вы видели хоть одно
message that a resident of Crimea stole a toilet bowl was
сообщение что житель Крыма стащил унитаз
not so true there
не было такого правда этого там
Leningrad region Moscow they are a
Ленинградская область Московская они там
spot like
пятно типа
normal people in Crimea they are not the only
нормальные люди в Крыму они не один
military from Crimea did not pull toilet bowls from
военные из Крыма не тянул унитазы из
Ukraine And why because this is the former
Украины А почему потому что это бывший
Ukraine they have toilet bowls logic is
Украины у них есть унитазы логика правда
true  well,
а хорошо
these are military personnel in the Crimea, then they are not
это военнослужащие в Крыму то они же не
all from Crimea, why don’t they drag the toilet bowl
все из Крыма почему они не тащат унитаза
because everyone at home already has toilet bowls in
потому что дома все уже с унитазами в
Crimea, you understand. And that is, for example
Крыму понимаете А то есть например
, somewhere in Berdyansk, there were toilet bowls at home,
где-нибудь в Бердянске дома были
too.
унитазов тоже придется это тоже Украина
when Yanukovych came to us By the way, yes, from
когда пришел Янукович Кстати да вот с
him This is a golden toilet remember that they
него Вот это золотой унитаз помните что
laughed for a reason it was a symbol of an
смеялись не просто так это был символ
advertising campaign  we had a toilet
рекламная кампания у нас была унитаз
Yanukovych said that Baton
Янукович сказал что Батон
google he had a golden long loaf a
погуглите у него был золотой батон
toilet a well-groomed hut we are Ukraine
унитаз ухоженную хатуша мы Украина
Russia he said so we should
Россия он так и сказал мы должны
be different they go into a hole in the street
отличаться они ходят в дырку на улице
and really under his rule we provide
и реально при его правлении обеспе
all the households of Ukraine with a toilet all in the
унитазом все домохозяйства Украины все в
Crimea in Donetsk in general  Donetsk the whole
Крыму в Донецке вообще вот Донецк весь
toilet bowl, he is the first Donetsk region, his
унитаза он первый Донецкий регион свои
Yenakiyevo toilet bowl immediately, that is, you
Енакиево унитазировал сразу то есть это
give the
даешь
toilet bowl the toilet bowl, I understand, and Putin is
унитазация унитазация я понял а Путин
watching the badge, the fly Yanukovych was able But I couldn’t
смотрит бляха муха Янукович смог А я не
[laughter]
[смех]
further Let's fish, let's be
дальше Давайте ловите рыбку давай
happy
счастливо